Andy Smith

Farnham, UK andy_smithy@hotmail.co.uk http://andysmith.me

I am a Graduate in Computer Science from Newcastle University and have a passion for technology. My interests lie both in back-end and front-end, and the thought of learning new technologies and developing my skills and experience further excites me greatly!

I also love outdoor sports such as skiing, camping, and climbing, and practicing and performing instruments such as the piano (17 years) and the violin (2 years).

Technical Skills

Likes: java, c++, android, c#, php, javascript, jquery, meteor

Dislikes: documentum, xcp2.x

Experience

UI Lead - CGI

May 2016 - Current

html, css, javascript, meteorjs, mongodb, elasticsearch, reactjs, node.js

Currently working as UI lead on a proof-of-concept project. My responsibilities include:

- Leading the UI development (client-side and server-side)
- · Ensuring quality control
- · Front-end component design and integration.

Software Developer - CGI

July 2014 - May 2016

java, documentum6.5, web-services, javascript, jquery, jsp, css, html

I worked as a full-stack software developer in the Justice sector. I work both back-end and front-end and I'm involved in many phases of the project life-cycle including design, development and implementation, and testing.

Main responsibilities include:

- · Feature planning and development
- Bug fixing
- Unit, regression and integration testing

Junior Technical Architect/Developer - Logica

January 2013 – August 2013

shell, jenkins, java, mysql, oracle, junit, jmock

I worked on system modernization with a team to assist in the specification and development of the client's security.

This role is mainly focused on technical architecture and development. My main responsibilities centered around:

- The development and maintenance of tools to support event analysis and alerting functions such as reporting and log parsing.
- Liaising with the requirements team to discuss new business rules that have been agreed on for integration.

Test Analyst – Logica

August 2012 – December 2012

hp-quality-center

I worked as a test analyst on a modernization project for a complex solution targeted at the companies internal asset delivery system.

- I worked closely with the testing and development team to effectively execute and edit test scripts based on the solution requirements specification.
- I used the HP Quality Center to handle and report system defects.

Education

Computer Science with Industrial Placement, BSc Honours – Newcastle University java, c++, android, php, mysql, shell, nesc, vdm++, jquery, css, html

2010 - 2014

A-Levels – St. Benet Biscop RC Catholic High School vba. actionscript-2, ms-office

2008 - 2010

Achieved A-Levels in ICT (Double Applied), Music, and Music Technology, including an A in ICT.

GCSEs – St. Benet Biscop RC Catholic High School ms-office

Achieved 11 GCSE's at grade A-C, including A's in Science, English and ICT.

Projects & Interests

Stack Overflow - http://stackoverflow.com/users/1295906

March 2012 - Current

November 2015 - September 2016

November 2015 - August 2016

August 2015 - March 2016

September 2016 - October 2016

Written 91 answers. Active in android.

 $\textbf{GitHub-AndySmith.me} - \underline{\text{https://github.com/Smittey/AndySmith}}$

html, javascript, jquery, css, last.fm

A personal website to display my projects, work timeline and skills

GitHub - Node.js-Projects - https://github.com/Smittey/Node.js-Projects

Node.js projects & scrips

php, slack-api, last.fm, youtube-api

GitHub - Jetsettr - https://github.com/Smittey/Jetsettr

javascript, meteor, leaflet

python, raspberry-pi, electronics

My home-made Raspberry Pi projects

Developer and core contributor.

My Gym Journal - Android Apps on Google Play - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=my.gym.journal

iava, android

Designed to help bodybuilders keep track of their progress

Designer, developer, tester

Using Meteor Offline - http://smittey.co.uk/using-meteor-offline/ Writing

Tips and tricks to workaround package management offline

The Insecurities of a Full-Stack Developer - http://smittey.co.uk/the-insecurities-of-a-full-stack-developer/

Coming to terms with the problems facing full-stack developers

2006 - 2008

July 2016

April 2016

May 2016

Developer and core contributor.

 $\textbf{GitHub-Smittey.co.uk} - \underline{\text{https://github.com/Smittey/Smittey}}$

html, javascript, jquery, css

My personal blog

Developer and core contributor.

Developer and core contributor.

GitHub - LittleFarnhamPianists.co.uk -

https://github.com/Smittey/LittleFarnhamPianists

html, javascript, jquery, css

A website for a local piano business

Developer and core contributor.

GitHub - Slack-apps - https://github.com/Smittey/Slack-apps

Plugins for Slack Messaging

Developer and core contributor.

A project which maps your Foursquare checkins as connected points, and provides you with calculated distances and other metrics

Developer and core contributor.

GitHub - AnybodyOn? - https://github.com/Smittey/RaspberryPi-Projects

Keeping Fit as a Programmer – http://smittey.co.uk/keeping-fit-as-a-programmer/

How exercising has affected my comfort at work